# Judah Avery TECHNICAL GAMEPLAY DESIGNER

## CONTACT

judahavery.com

in linkedin.com/in/judahavery

judahbavery@gmail.com

<u>(802)-777-0970</u>

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Unreal Engine 4/5
- Unreal Blueprint
- Unity
- C++ / C#
- Visual Studio
- Maya / Blender
- Confluence
- Jira
- Perforce
- Adobe Suite

## PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Technical Design
- Systems Design
- Combat Design
- Enemy Al Design
- Visual Design
- Prototyping
- Design Documentation
- Strong Design Sense
- Working Under Deadlines

#### **INTERESTS**

- Surfing
- Snowboarding & Skiing
- Running & Hiking
- Tabletop Games

## **SUMMARY**

Passionate designer experienced with building AAA quality systems in both technical and combat design roles. Self-driven workflow coupled with experience collaborating alongside engineers, artists, sound designers and animators. Very eager and adaptable team member that's always happy to help.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Unannounced Project - Respawn Entertainment**

Combat Designer | December 2023 - Present

- Responsible for multiple enemy AI, pitching the initial design, prototyping, and iterating through team feedback and playtesting
- Direct collaboration across departments, especially animation, tweaking enemy attack timing, tells, anticipation, navigation, personality, etc.
- Ownership of multiple combat systems, working extensively with Unreal Blueprint, behavior trees, animation montages, and animation blueprints

# Star Wars: Jedi Survivor - Respawn Entertainment

Technical Designer | Shipped Title | August 2022 - December 2023

- Unreal blueprint expert and point of contact for support with Unreal Engine
- Responsible for multiple game systems, unique AI behaviors, UI/UX features, level design features, and more
- Direct collaboration with Level Design, Encounters, Sound Design, Animation, Destruction, UI/UX, QA, Code, and departmental leads/directors
- At the finaling stage, helped to hunt down, reproduce, and solve bugs to bring the game to ship

## Technical Design Intern | May 2022 - August 2022

- Interned while pursuing a bachelors in Game Design, where I was offered an immediate full time role, which I accepted in place of finishing my degree
- Acted with similar responsibilities to the above role, though smaller in scale

## OTHER PROJECTS

## Champlain College - The Game Studio | August 2019 - May 2022

- Collaborated with other multidisciplinary students to mimic industry workflows through small teams
- Often led the design of these projects and assisted the production, helping to steer the creative direction and keep the team on track for milestone goals
- Responsible for design documentation, systems design/programming,
  UI design/programming, and animation implementation

# SNIPERPUNK | UI Designer & Web Developer | February 2021 - May 2022

- Passion project built by a group of students from Champlain College, still currently under development with the help of an independent publisher
- Fast-paced, top-down hero shooter with online multiplayer and pinball inspired combat

## **EDUCATION**

## High School Diploma | Computer Animation & Web Design

Center For Technology, Essex, Vermont | 2017 - 2019

- Started pursuing game design/development through a tech program in my final two years of high school
- Competed in nation-wide game development competitions both years after qualifying through placing 1st in the state